Jacob W. Greene

537 NW 34 Terrace Gainesville, Florida, 32607 T: (904) 303-7677 E: jacobwgreene@ufl.edu



Summary

I am a Phd student in the Department of English at the University of Florida. I specialize in writing and media studies, and my research focuses on the rhetorical application of augmented reality technology as an emerging form of interventionist writing. My other research interests include digital rhetorics, visual rhetoric, composition pedagogy, environmental rhetoric, and circulation studies.

Education

Phd in English, University of Florida 2017

MA in English, Clemson University 2013

BA in English, University of North Florida 2010

Positions

Coordinator, Trace ARCs Project

2014-Present

- Developed mobile augmented reality applications for Android and iOS
- Led collaborative digital humanities projects with scholars from other departments and institutions

Treasurer, Digital Assembly

2014-Present

- Co-organized annual digital media conference
- Maintained budget and submitted other financial documents

Graduate Committee Chair, University Writing Program

Spring 2014

- Co-designed several thematic first year writing courses
- Solicited and organized teaching materials for new instructors

Writing Tutor, Vickery Student Athlete Enrichment Center

Summer 2012

• Tutored student athletes in writing intensive courses

Editorial Assistant, Clemson University Digital Press

2011-2012

- Copy-edited and formatted scholarly publications
- Maintained contact with authors and contributors
- Designed covers for bi-annual journal and other publications

Courses Taught

ENC 1145: Writing About Screens

ENC 2210: Technical Writing

ENG 1131: Writing Through Augmented Reality

ENC 3254: Writing in the Disciplines

ENC 1102: Rhetoric and Academic Research

ENG 103: Accelerated Composition

AML 2070: Survey of American Literature

Publications

"Premediating Ecological Crisis: A Visual Rhetoric of Florida Sinkholes." Forthcoming in *The Journal of Florida Studies* 1.4 (2015). Web.

"Teaching Media Critique Through *The Colbert Report*: Toward a Parodic Pedagogy." Forthcoming In *Through a Distorted Lens: Media as Curricula and Pedagogy in the 21st Century.* Ed. Goldstein, Rebecca and Laura Nicosia. Rotterdam: Sense Publishers. 2015.

"The Media's Dirty War on Occupy." *Against the Current*. (July/August 2012): 9-10. Print.

Invited Presentations

"What is Augmented Reality Criticism?" Co-presentation with Sidney I. Dobrin. Marston Science Library iSTEAM Speaker Series. September 2, 2015.

"Augmented Reality." Faculty Workshop. University of North Florida. April 6, 2015.

"MassMine: Creating, Curating, and Data Mining Social Media." Co-presentation with Aaron Beveridge. University of Florida Digital Humanities Working Group Training. November 13, 2014.

Conferences

"Writing through Augmented Reality." *Risk and Reward*: Conference on College Composition and Communication. Tampa, FL. (2015).

"Beyond Gimmick: Augmenting Technical Writing Pedagogy." *Exploring the Value of Technical Communication. Association of Teachers of Technical Writing.* Tampa, FL. (2015).

"Gestural Rhetorics and the Natural User Interface." *Entering the Conversation: Inaugural Cultural Rhetorics Conference*. Michigan State University. (2014).

"Kinect for Windows: The New (Inter)Face of Error in Digital Media?" *Syst3m Error:* Ruptures in Digital Media. University of Florida. (2014).

"Reading Ecologies: Researching to a new (Algo)rithm." *English Graduate Organization Conference*. University of Florida. (2013).

"Would Walter Benjamin Play the XBox Kinect?" *Critiquing Culture Conference*. George Mason University. (2012).

"Boundaries of the Immigrant Body in Dirty Pretty Things." *South Atlantic Modern Language Association*. Durham, NC. (2012).

"Designing Waste in Media Representations of the Occupy Movement." *Occupied: Taking up Space and Time*. Indiana University-Bloomington. (2012).

Grants/Awards

College of Liberal Arts & Sciences Travel Grant. (2014).

Student nomination to Difference Makers Project. Clemson University. (2013).

Software/Languages

- Unity Game Engine, Vuforia SDK, Blender, Aurasma Studio
- Adobe Photoshop, InDesign, and Premiere
- HTML, CSS (Intermediate)
- C# (Beginner)